horizonsunlimited.com 2006-03-29

# Horizons Unlimited Global Enterprises Privacy Policy

 | 

### Privacy Policy for Horizons Unlimited Global Enterprises Inc. 

| 

| 

in co-operation with  

---  

221 days left before the HU Travellers Meeting in Belgium, September 8-10 - Register now!  
There's 8 fun and inspirational Meetings this year - plan on getting to at least one!  
 **The Achievable Dream DVD -How to ride the world - get it NOW and save!**

| 

Home  
  
---  
Our Trip  
Who Are We?  
  
E-zine  
  
HUBB  
  
HU Souk  
  
HU Travellers Meetings  
  
Trip Planning  
  
Travellers' Stories  
  
Links  
  
Community  
  
Misc Bike Tech  
  
Motorcycle Art  
  
Site Info  
  
Advertise here!  
Support our sponsors  
Join - Become a  
Member of HU  
Comments  
Contact Us  
Contribute Info  
Guestbook  
Privacy Policy  
Search  
Site Map  
  
We respect the privacy of our travellers: those who subscribe to the e-zine, those who e-mail us or contact us, those who use and provide information on the Horizons Unlimited Bulletin Board (HUBB), and those who post their travellers stories (blogs) on the site. 

#### What information do we collect and why

**It is our policy** to respect the purpose for which our site visitors gave us information. 

The type of information we collect may include names, e-mail addresses, nationality and type of motorcycle ridden.

The purposes for which we collect information about individuals include the following: 

  * obtaining and responding to feedback from travellers

  * allowing people to share their experiences with fellow travellers on the HUBB, via forms (e.g. Shipping, Border Crossings) and in the e-zine

  * administering the HUBB to make it the best possible experience for the motorcycle travellers' community

  * contacting travellers about HUBB postings, shipping or border crossing experiences

  * sending our monthly newsletter to travellers who ask for it

  * organising Horizons Unlimited Travellers Meetings, including registering participants (for these events only, we request a mobile phone number for participants, to use in the unlikely situation that we have to contact them about changes or cancellations while they are on route to the event) 

  * preparing listings of businesses which we deem of interest to our readers for our Links or Shippers pages or in the newsletter 

#### Subscriptions

**It is our policy** to send the ezine only to those who request it (that is, opt-in). We remove names immediately upon request through convenient unsubscribe links in every mailing. Every issue of our ezine clearly explains how to unsubscribe. 

We will NOT correspond with you to sell you anything.

#### Third Party Use

**It is our policy** to not sell, rent, or loan our subscriber lists to third parties for e-mail marketing. Who is a third party? Well, the first party is you, the second party is us, so it's basically anyone who's not you or us. 

While we sell advertising in our ezine and on the site to other companies, we never allow third parties any use of these subscriber lists.

#### Security and Disclosure on the Site

**It is our policy** to store subscriber and password files with personal information in a secure manner. We store such files in areas not accessible to Web browsers, behind password protection, or off-line.

Spammers collect e-mail addresses from html web pages using robots (spambots). We use encoded e-mail addresses that a spambot can't read, but your browser can, throughout the site, and in forms where possible, to protect e-mail addresses from being 'harvested' in this manner.

##### Horizons Unlimited Bulletin Board (HUBB)

When you register for the HUBB, you can choose whether your e-mail address will be visible (via the profile link) to other users. You can access and update your personal information in the 'profile' section at any time. 

We recommend NOT putting your e-mail address in a posting. If someone needs your e-mail address they can get it by clicking on the profile link  at the top of your post, or clicking on the next link over  to send you an e-mail. 

Why is this important? The HUBB pages are ordinary html web pages, like 99.99% of the web, which means that a spambot can read your e-mail address and "harvest" it, and add you to their list of people to send spam to. The reason we have the link is to prevent this \- your e-mail address is hidden from spambots by code behind this link to protect your privacy from junk mailers. 

##### Submitting information on Forms

When you submit shipment information via the Shipping form, you must register and provide us with your e-mail address so we can contact you if necessary about your shipment details. We do not accept anonymous shipment postings (to prevent shipping companies or individuals from posting advertisements under the guise of shipment details), and your full name will be included in the shipment posting, but your e-mail address is not disclosed unless YOU put it into the details of the shipment. We recommend you NOT do this, for the reasons above.

This is for YOUR protection. Your security and privacy is important to us, and we do all we can to ensure it.

| 

Check out the [ ](http://www.cafepress.com/horizonsmc)Books pages for Travel books and videos. Remember if you go to Amazon from our books page, we get a small percentage of every purchase.  
Thanks! Grant and Susan 

| 

#### Cookies

**It is our policy** to use cookies in a responsible manner to help our visitors, not snoop on them. 'Cookies' are small files of data that we send to your computer so the software can 'recognize' you when you return. We use two types of cookies: 

We send a 'session cookie' to your computer if and when you log in to enter or edit your shipments or travellers details by entering your e-mail address and password. These cookies allow us to recognize you if you use multiple pages in our site during the same session, so that you don't need to re-enter your password multiple times. Once you log out or close your browser, these session cookies expire and no longer have any effect.

Please note that when you are finished, if you are on a shared computer, in an internet cafe etc, for your security you should always logout of ANY system you are logged into, be it here, or Hotmail / Yahoo etc. Also, you should close all browser windows, delete temporary files and the history of sites visited.

At your option (when you register for the HUBB), we also use longer-lasting cookies on the HUBB bulletin board to allow the software to recognize you as a HUBB user if you return to the HUBB using the same computer and browser. 

We do NOT collect or use information from cookies to develop a profile about our visitors or shoppers. 

#### Web Site Traffic Information

**It is our policy** to use web site traffic information only to try to understand our readers' preferences better and to manage the load on our servers, so as to improve our service and your experience with the site.

Because of the way that World Wide Web communication standards work, when you arrive at or leave the Horizons Unlimited Web site, we automatically receive the Web address of the site that you came from. We also collect information on which pages you visit while you are on the Horizons Unlimited site, the type of browser you use and the times you access our Web site. None of this information is linked to you as an individual. 

#### Notification of Changes

**It is our policy** to be as informative as possible about changes to this privacy policy. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes so travellers are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an e-mail to the address they have registered with us, and post it on the site. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

#### Applicability of this Policy

This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by Horizons Unlimited Global Enterprises Inc. via the Horizons Unlimited Web site, the HUBB, travellers' stories and information submitted on forms or via e-mail.

The Horizons Unlimited web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that Horizons Unlimited is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage travellers to be aware of this when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. 

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions or concerns about any aspect of this policy, please let us know. 

Thanks for your trust and support.

Grant and Susan Johnson  
Horizons Unlimited Global Enterprises Inc.

|   
---|---|---  
  
_Editors note:  
_We accept no responsibility for any of the above information in any way whatsoever. You are reminded to **do your own research.** Any commentary is strictly a personal opinion of the person supplying the information and is not to be construed as an endorsement of any kind.
